♪You crossed the sea of ​​stars and came with light♪
♪เธอมาจากฟากฟ้า มาพร้อมกับแสงสว่าง♪
♪My heart is like the dust, and I couldn't bear to stain the hemline♪
♪หัวใจฉันเปรียบเหมือนฝุ่น ไม่อยากแปดเปื้อนกระโปรงของเธอ♪
♪To love in a different way, the fireworks are in the stars' good graces♪
♪ความรักที่ไม่เหมือนใคร ดอกไม้ไฟที่ดวงดาวยังชายตามอง♪
♪I turn around and realize that my heart is empty ♪
♪หันกลับมาจึงเข้าใจ หัวใจนี้ยังว่างเปล่า♪
♪I miss the overflowing galaxy surging into the sea♪
♪ความคิดถึงท่วมท้นจักรวาล เอ่อล้นจนเต็มท้องทะเล♪
♪Even the fireworks desire to give the stars a future♪
♪ดอกไม้ไฟอยากเป็นที่พึ่งพิงให้ดวงดาว♪
♪As long as you are around♪
♪ขอเพียงแค่มีเธออยู่♪
♪Even the fireworks fear to bloom♪
♪ดอกไม้ไฟกลัวจะแตกแล้วดับไป♪
♪Looking at you, the light in your eyes dimmed♪
♪มองดูนัยน์ตาของเธอ แสงไฟค่อย ๆ เลือนหาย♪
♪I laughed at myself and that I deserve it ♪
♪ทำได้แต่สมน้ำหน้าตัวเอง♪
♪My heart skips a beat, but I'm afraid I'm not worthy of the future that you desire♪
♪ฉันใจสั่น♪
=You Are My Glory=
=ดุจดวงดาวเกียรติยศ=
=Episode 10=
=ตอนที่ 10=
Verify this data again.
ตรวจสอบดาต้าพวกนี้อีกครั้ง
Then record it.
แล้วบันทึกไว้ด้วย
Mr. Yu.
คุณอวี๋
You should eat first.
กินข้าวก่อนเถอะครับ
The cafeteria will close at one.
เดี๋ยวบ่ายโมงโรงอาหารก็ปิดแล้ว
You still have to eat something.
ยังไงก็ต้องกินข้าวนะ
(It's so familiar.)
(ฉันก็ว่าทำไมคุ้นจัง)
(I saw her ad today,
(วันนี้เห็นโฆษณา)
and remembered)
(ถึงนึกขึ้นมาได้)
(your classmate that day
(เพื่อนของนายวันนั้น)
was Qiao Jingjing.)
(คือเฉียวจิงจิง)
(Spend some more time together)
(มีเวลามากขึ้น อยู่ด้วยกันมากขึ้น)
(Sorry, Mrs. Wang.)
(อาจารย์ครับ ขอโทษนะครับ)
(I just got your message.)
(ผมเพิ่งเห็นวีแชทของอาจารย์)
(It's her.)
(ใช่ครับ)
Why didn't you invite me for lunch?
กินข้าวไม่เรียกกันเลยนะ
I saw you doze off at your desk,
ผมเห็นพี่นอนฟุบอยู่บนโต๊ะ
so I didn't call you.
ก็เลยไม่เรียก
I brought you some food.
ผมเอาข้าวมาเผื่อ
Let's eat outside and get us some fresh air.
กินข้างนอกนี่แหละ สูดอากาศหน่อย
I'm getting older, not like I used to be.
อายุมากแล้ว ไม่เหมือนเมื่อก่อน
I don't know what's come over me,
ช่วงนี้ไม่รู้เป็นอะไร
dozing off a lot lately.
ง่วงตลอดเลย
Why didn't you order noodles?
ทำไมไม่สั่งเส้นหมี่ล่ะ
You're not having noodles here in Xi'an?
มาซีอานแต่ไม่กินเมนูเส้น
We have oily noodles, saozi noodles.
โย๋วพอเมี่ยน เส้าจือเมี่ยน
They're delicious.
อร่อยจะตาย
You don't know when to eat it.
ก็ไม่รู้ว่าพี่จะกินเมื่อไหร่
Noodles lump easily.
พวกเส้นมันอืดง่าย
You're particular.
ขนาดนั้นเชียว
By the way,
ใช่สิ
I received a message
ตอนฉันออกมา
right when I came out.
มีข่าวมาว่า
The ESA's Tycho Brahe
ทิโค บราห์ของสถานียุโรป
was also affected by the solar wind.
ก็ได้รับผลจากลมสุริยะเหมือนกัน
Their situation is worse than ours.
สถานการณ์แย่กว่าพวกเราอีก
They announced that they gave up on saving it.
มีการประกาศยกเลิกการช่วยเหลือแล้ว
The Brahe?
ทิโค บราห์
The one they launched last year?
ที่เพิ่งส่งไปเมื่อปีที่แล้วเหรอ
They said,
ได้ยินว่า
its power supply got hit hard,
กระทบต่อระบบจ่ายพลังงานโดยตรง
so it's hopeless.
กู้ไม่ได้แล้ว
JX has only been out for more than a year.
JX ก็เพิ่งส่งไปได้ปีกว่า
It's supposed to last five years.
มีอายุการใช้งานที่ออกแบบไว้ห้าปี
It hasn't completed its mission.
ภารกิจยังไม่สำเร็จเลย
So many stars are yet to be seen.
ยังไม่ได้สำรวจดาวอีกหลายดวง
My,
นายเนี่ยนะ
you sound artsy all of a sudden.
เกิดเป็นศิลปินขึ้นมาซะงั้น
Let me correct you.
ฉันขอแก้อะไรหน่อย
JX is to observe the earth.
JX ทำภารกิจสำรวจโลก
It's a quote from Jade Rabbit's Weibo.
เวยป๋อของกระต่ายหยกบอกไว้อย่างนี้
Someone told me that.
มีคนเคยบอกผม
You didn't take a hint, did you?
พี่นี่ไม่ใฝ่รู้อะไรเลย
Look on the bright side.
มองในแง่ดีหน่อย
JX will not end up like Brahe.
JX ไม่เหมือนทิโค บราห์
At least we have
อย่างน้อยพวกเราก็ปรับตำแหน่ง
successfully established
หันเข้าหาดวงอาทิตย์ได้แล้ว
sun orientation regular recharge.
การชาร์จไฟปกติ
These past few days,
สองสามวันนี้
every step in the way,
แต่ละเรื่องแต่ละด่าน
it's been suspenseful.
มันลุ้นน่าดู
We figured out
พวกเราเจอว่า
that our attitude orbit control
ระบบควบคุมทิศทาง
may have abnormalities,
อาจเกิดความผิดปกติ
but we did not expect
แต่คิดไม่ถึงว่า
the main interface to be broken too.
จุดเชื่อมต่อหลักก็เสียหายด้วย
By the way,
ใช่สิ
currently, the earth-oriented
ตอนนี้มอเตอร์ควบคุมทิศทาง
attitude maneuver
ที่บังคับให้หันหาผิวโลก
can only be implemented by the backup.
ต้องใช้เครื่องสำรองทำงาน
We still have to optimize
พวกเรายังต้องปรับแผนการทำงาน
the implementation strategy.
ให้ดีขึ้นอีกหน่อย
I have to go back.
ผมเข้าไปก่อนนะ
You haven't finished your lunch.
ยังกินไม่เสร็จเลย
I have.
กินเสร็จแล้ว
What a workaholic.
พวกบ้างาน
(Attention, all units.)
ทุกตำแหน่งโปรดทราบ
The Jiamusi Station reports
สถานีเจียมู่ซือรายงานว่า
that the satellite will make entry in one minute.
อีกหนึ่งนาทีดาวเทียมเข้าระยะ
Let's hope nothing goes wrong.
อย่าผิดพลาดตรงไหนอีกนะ
(Attention, all units.)
ทุกตำแหน่งโปรดทราบ
(The Jiamusi Station reports)
สถานีเจียมู่ซือรายงานว่า
(that the satellite has made entry.)
ดาวเทียมเข้าสู่ระยะแล้ว
(Real-time fault diagnosis system for on-orbit spacecraft)
(การวิเคราะห์ข้อมูลดาวเทียม JX-1)
According to telemetry data,
จากการตรวจจับสัญญาณระยะไกล
all systems are working normally
ระบบทุกอย่างทำงานปกติ
and it is conditioned for attitude maneuvering.
พร้อมสำหรับการขับเคลื่อนส่วนควบคุมทิศทาง
As planned,
ดำเนินการตามแผน
send the Satellite-to-Earth Orientation Command Sequence
ส่งชุดคำสั่งปรับทิศดาวเทียม
right away.
หันเข้าพื้นโลก
(Real-time fault diagnosis system for on-orbit spacecraft)
(การวิเคราะห์ข้อมูลดาวเทียม JX-1)
(The satellite has entered earth orientation mode.)
ดาวเทียมได้เข้าสู่โหมดปรับทิศ เข้าหาพื้นโลกแล้วครับ
(Attitude normal.)
สถานการณ์ปกติ
(All system parameters normal.)
ค่าระบบต่าง ๆ ปกติ
(It is now conditioned
พร้อมสำหรับภารกิจ
for on-orbit missions.)
ตามวงโคจรในขั้นถัดไป
We did it!
เยี่ยม เยี่ยม เยี่ยม
Thank you.
ขอบคุณนะ ขอบคุณนะ ขอบคุณนะ
Mr. Li,
เหล่าหลี่
thank you.
ขอบคุณนะครับ
Thank you for rescuing
ขอบคุณที่พวกคุณร่วมมือกับพวกเรา
this satellite with us.
ในภารกิจกู้ดาวเทียมดวงนี้
It's our responsibility.
มันเป็นหน้าที่ของเราอยู่แล้ว
We're satellite herders.
คนเลี้ยงดาวนิ
The satellite is yours
ดาวเทียมเป็นของพวกคุณ
and ours too.
แล้วก็เป็นของพวกเราด้วย
Yeah.
ใช่
We'd like these young people
ต้องให้เด็กหนุ่มพวกนี้
to get some rest.
รีบไปพักผ่อน
They haven't slept much lately.
หลายวันนี้แทบไม่ได้นอนเลย
Mr. Hu.
หัวหน้าหู
I'm impressed
หนุ่ม ๆ ของพวกคุณ
by your younger members.
ฝีมือใช้ได้เลยนะ
The same goes for your unit.
ของพวกคุณก็เหมือนกันแหละ
They're all fine young people.
มีแต่คนมีฝีมือ
Dedicated, persistent, and full of ideas.
เคารพหน้าที่ ยึดมั่น มีความคิด
They carry our hopes for the future of aerospace.
เป็นความหวังของวงการอวกาศของพวกเรา
You've been out for a month.
นี่นายหายตัวไปเดือนนึง
You're as sharp as ever.
สมองยังใช้ได้นะเนี่ย
You're still thinking one step ahead.
คิดเร็วกว่าคนอื่นหนึ่งก้าวเสมอ
You deserve praise too.
ผลัดกันชมบ้างนะ
Mr. Guan,
ความสามารถ
your orbit simulation calculation capability
ในการคำนวณการจำลองวงโคจรของคุณกวน
is also very amazing.
ก็ไม่เบาเลยนะ
Even Mr. Li was about to poach you on the spot.
หัวหน้าหลี่แทบอยากจะซื้อตัวไปตอนนั้นเลย
Good news
ก็ดีนะ
can put Mr. Hu on edge.
ทำให้เหล่าหูตื่นเต้นซะบ้าง
But the lifespan of the satellite
แต่ว่าอายุของดาวเทียม
was still affected.
ก็ได้รับผลกระทบเหมือนกัน
Still, it could exceed its planned lifespan.
ยังไงก็ยังเกินอายุที่คำนวณไว้อยู่ดี
Should be way more than that.
เพียงแค่แต่เดิมควรจะ เกินอายุไปได้มากกว่านี้
It's already very lucky
แค่กู้กลับมาได้
to be rescued.
ก็โชคดีมากแล้ว
This satellite,
ดาวเทียมดวงนี้
you participated in the design
เป็นดาวเทียมดวงแรก
of the first model.
ที่นายเข้าร่วมการออกแบบด้วย
It was the first time we worked together.
และก็เป็นดวงแรกที่เราร่วมมือกัน
Do you know how I felt
รู้ไหมว่าตอนเจอนายครั้งแรก
when I first met you?
รู้สึกยังไง
You were jealous?
อิจฉาน่ะสิ
It was quite obvious.
ชัดเจนอยู่แล้ว
Nah.
ถุย
When I first met you,
ตอนเจอนายครั้งแรก
I thought
ฉันคิดว่า
you were keeping up appearances.
ก็แค่พวกหน้าตาดี
It didn't take long
แต่พอผ่านไปไม่นาน
before you gave me
ก็ทำให้ฉันได้เห็น
a detailed plan of the information flow interface.
ข้อมูลที่หลั่งไหลเข้ามา
So I thought,
ในใจคิดว่า ใช้ได้นี่
your talent was as good as your looks,
ต้องอย่างนี้สิทั้งเก่งทั้งหน้าตาดี
so we'd make a good couple.
เป็นคู่ขาที่ดีเลย
Watch your words.
เลือกคำให้ดีหน่อย
You're making us engineering students turn red,
อย่าทำเสียหน้านักศึกษาวิศวกรอย่างพวกเรา
okay?
ได้ไหม
Shall we...
เรามา
talk about our finances?
คุยเรื่องเงินกันดีกว่า
Did the professor tell you?
อาจารย์บอกพี่แล้วเหรอ
When Mr. Zhang called me,
ผอ.จางโทรหาฉันแล้ว
I wished I could beat around the bush.
หวังว่าฉันจะช่วยคุยกับนายได้
Are you facing any difficulties?
นายมีปัญหาอะไรหรือเปล่า
Or...
หรือว่า
is it about your family?
เกี่ยวกับครอบครัวหรือเปล่า
By the way,
ใช่สิ
I remember
ฉันจำได้ว่าครั้งก่อน
after you answered a call from your family,
ที่นายรับโทรศัพท์จากที่บ้าน
something was up with you the next day.
พออีกวันนึงก็ผิดปกติ
No, not at all.
ที่บ้านไม่มีอะไร
I was just flustered.
ผมแค่สับสน
Glad to hear that.
ไม่มีอะไรก็ดี
I'm a little curious.
แต่ฉันสงสัยว่า
Are investment banks really profitable?
สายลงทุนทำเงินมากขนาดนั้นเหรอ
You earned over a million upon graduation.
ที่บอกว่าจบใหม่ก็ได้เป็นล้าน
Really?
เป็นอย่างนั้นจริงหรือเปล่า
Well...
เรื่องนี้
It depends on the situation.
ก็แล้วแต่คนแล้วแต่เวลา
Before the 2008 financial crisis,
ก่อนวิกฤตเศรษฐกิจปีศูนย์แปด
someone could achieve it.
มีคนทำได้จริง ๆ
By the time I graduated,
แต่ตอนที่ผมจบ
the crisis was abating.
เพิ่งจะฟื้นจากวิกฤตเศรษฐกิจใหม่ ๆ
It wasn't too bad.
ก็ยังพอได้
If I were in Google,
ถ้าฉันอยู่ที่กูเกิ้ล
I'd earn huge paychecks.
ก็เงินเดือนสูงนะ
Rather than Google,
อย่าว่าแต่กูเกิ้ล
how about NASA?
วงการอวกาศที่อเมริกาก็ไม่เลว
But we're merely foreigners there.
เพียงแค่ในฐานะคนต่างชาติ
We'll probably
ชาตินี้พวกเราก็คงไม่ได้
never have access to their core tech.
เข้าใกล้เทคโนโลยีที่เป็นแกนหลักจริง ๆ
Do you know
นายรู้ไหมว่าทำไม
why I never urged you to stay?
ฉันไม่เคยรั้งนายไว้เลย
Because I never thought
เพราะฉันคิดว่าถึงยังไง
you'd leave.
นายก็ไม่ไป
I thought we're two peas in a pod.
ฉันรู้สึกว่าเราสองคนเป็นประเภทเดียวกัน
Just like my wife said,
เหมือนที่เมียฉันบอก
simply put,
เธอว่า
it was untimely.
พวกไม่ทันยุค
I also made a bet with my folks
ฉันยังพนันกับพวกเขาเลยว่า
that if you were really leaving,
ถ้านายไปจริง ๆ
I'd change my name
ฉันยอมเปลี่ยนชื่อเลย
to Pigpen Guan.
เป็นกวนไจ้งั่งทั้งโคตร
Wouldn't that be a reunion?
นั่นมันทั้งตระกูลเลยนะ
We're all siblings, right?
พี่น้องกันแท้ ๆ
Shut up.
ไปไกล ๆ เลย
Aren't you and I brothers?
นายไม่ใช่น้องฉัน
Can I ask you something, Yu Tu?
ฉันมีเรื่องจะถามนายหน่อย อวี๋ถู
About the satellite failure,
อุบัติเหตุดาวเทียมครั้งนี้
no one could tell what caused it.
ไม่มีใครรู้ว่า
We solved it in five days.
เราจะจัดการได้ภายในห้าวัน
Some cases took us
อาจจะต้องใช้เวลา
months to solve.
รายเดือนก็ได้
If it really takes months,
ถ้าใช้เวลาหลายเดือนจริง ๆ
will your investment bank wait?
งานด้านลงทุนจะยังรอนายไหม
Or...
หรือว่า
Would you run away
นายจะไม่สนทางนี้
and abandon us?
แล้วทิ้งพวกเราไปเลย
It's almost 5 am.
จะตีห้าแล้ว
Jing should be up by now.
พี่สะใภ้นายคงจะตื่นแล้วมั้ง
By the way.
ใช่สิ
How's it going
ช่วงนี้พี่กับพี่สะใภ้
between both of you?
ไม่มีปัญหากันใช่ไหม
Nothing.
จะมีเรื่องอะไรได้
She has a junior
เธอมีรุ่นน้องผู้หญิงคนหนึ่ง
whom she'd like to introduce to you.
อยากแนะนำให้รู้จักนาย
Last time she saw
คราวก่อนที่ได้เห็น
our group photo
รูปถ่ายเราสองคน
and asked if you have a girlfriend.
ก็ถามทันทีว่านายมีแฟนหรือยัง
You're so good-looking,
คนหน้าตาดี
so you stand a good chance.
มันได้เปรียบจริง ๆ นะเนี่ย
But it took Jing
ตอนนั้นที่ฉันตามตื๊อพี่สะใภ้ของนาย
a lot of effort to court me.
ต้องทุ่มทุนลงแรงไปเท่าไหร่
Turn her down for me.
ช่วยผมปฏิเสธหน่อยแล้วกัน
You really don't need one?
ไม่สนใจเหรอ
But I met her.
ฉันเคยเจอนะ
She's quite pretty.
สวยอยู่นะ
Please, no.
ไม่ต้องหรอกครับ
Recently...
ช่วงนี้
I met
ผมได้รู้จัก
a girl.
สาว
She's quite clever,
คล่องแคล่วดี
a little mischievous,
ดื้อนิดหน่อย
and receptive.
แต่ก็เชื่อฟังดี
That's great.
ใช้ได้นี่
You met her on vacation?
รู้จักกันตอนลาพักเหรอ
No.
ไม่ใช่ครับ
We're from the same high school.
เป็นเพื่อนม.ปลาย
From the same high school?
เพื่อนม.ปลาย
Why are you dating with her only now?
แล้วทำไมเพิ่งได้คุยกัน
Back then,
เมื่อก่อนนี้
I had poor judgment.
ผมดูคนไม่เป็น
So I didn't date her.
เลยไม่ได้คุย
You're kidding me.
ไม่ใช่มั้ง
Is it because she doesn't like you?
เธออาจไม่ชอบนายมากกว่า
But I don't think so.
ผมว่าคงไม่ถึงขั้นนั้น
You still got it.
เขี้ยวเล็บยังใช้ได้นะ
It's locked.
ทำไมประตูล็อคล่ะเนี่ย
Not a soul in sight.
ไม่มีคนอยู่ด้วย
Maybe they're busy.
คงไปทำธุระมั้ง
Just keep waiting.
รออีกเดี๋ยว
In ten minutes,
อีกสิบนาที
Jing should be up from bed.
พี่สะใภ้นายก็จะตื่นแล้ว
Then we'll call her,
เดี๋ยวต้องโทรหาเธอหน่อย
tell her I'm safe,
ตอกบัตรสักนิด
so we don't have to go in.
ไม่งั้นเดี๋ยวพอเข้าไป
Otherwise, once it gets warmer,
เจอลมอุ่น ๆ
I'll go out like a light.
พอหัวถึงหมอนก็หลับเลย
Let's rest here for now.
พักกันก่อน
(Yu Tu.)
(อวี๋ถู)
(I hope)
(เรื่องที่จะลาออก)
(you'll reconsider your resignation.)
(ลองคิดดูอีกทีนะ)
(You belong to aerospace.)
(นายเป็นคนของอวกาศ)
(Luckily, I'm fine.)
(ดีนะที่คราวนี้ฉันไม่เป็นอะไร)
(Otherwise, we'll end up spending)
(ไม่งั้นเงินในบ้านมีอยู่แค่นี้)
(what's left of our savings.)
(ไม่พอใช้จ่ายแน่)
(At times like this,)
(ถึงตอนนี้ก็เริ่มรู้สึกว่า)
(I think)
(ลูก)
(our son doesn't need to be a high achiever.)
(ไม่ต้องได้ดีมากก็ได้)
(He might as well find a job)
(อยู่ที่บ้านเก่าของเรา)
(in our little hometown)
(หางานทำในเมืองเล็ก ๆ)
(or dabble in finance.)
(ทำพวกด้านการเงินก็ได้)
(At least he'll have some free time.)
(อย่างน้อยก็ยังมีอิสระ)
(Can I ask you something, Yu Tu?)
(ฉันมีเรื่องจะถามนายหน่อย อวี๋ถู)
(If it really takes months,)
(ถ้าใช้เวลาหลายเดือนจริง ๆ)
(will your investment bank wait?)
(งานด้านลงทุนจะยังรอนายไหม)
(Or...)
(หรือว่า)
(will you run away)
(นายจะไม่สนทางนี้)
(and abandon us?)
(แล้วทิ้งพวกเราไปเลย)
(Yu Tu.)
(อวี๋ถู)
(I'm so disappointed at you.)
นายทำให้ฉันผิดหวังจริง ๆ
(Do you know why)
(นายรู้ไหมว่าทำไม)
(I never urged you to stay?)
(ฉันไม่เคยรั้งนายไว้เลย)
(Because I never thought)
(เพราะฉันคิดว่าถึงยังไง)
(you'd leave.)
(นายก็ไม่ไป)
(I wish more than anyone else)
ฉันเป็นคนที่อยากให้นาย
(for you to remain)
เป็นวิศวกรอวกาศต่อไป
(an aerospace designer.)
มากที่สุดแล้ว
We can call her now.
โทรหาพี่สะใภ้ได้แล้ว
Easy there.
ค่อย ๆ
You should take it easy a few days
น่าจะอยู่อีกสักพัก
before you return to Shanghai.
ค่อยกลับเซี่ยงไฮ้
I'll have to go back sooner or later.
ถึงยังไงก็ต้องกลับเซี่ยงไฮ้อยู่ดี
I'm getting homesick.
คิดถึงบ้าน
Once I'm there,
ไว้พอถึงเซี่ยงไฮ้
I'll head straight home.
ฉันจะเข้าบ้านก่อน
You should go home and rest too.
นายก็กลับไปพักก่อน
You don't have to take me
โรงพยาบาลที่เซี่ยงไฮ้
to hospital in Shanghai.
นายไม่ต้องไปเป็นเพื่อนฉันหรอก
No.
ไม่ได้
I'll speak to her
ให้ฉันเป็นคน
alone.
บอกเมียฉันเองดีกว่า
So...
งั้น
I will take you downstairs.
ผมจะไปส่งพี่ที่ใต้ตึก
(Shen Jing)
(เสิ่นจิ้ง)
She asked me yesterday,
(เมื่อวานเธอถามฉันว่า)
when I'll be home.
(จะกลับกันเมื่อไหร่)
I didn't reply.
(ฉันไม่ได้บอก)
What should I tell her?
ฉันจะพูดยังไงดี
I promised her last year
ปีที่แล้วบอกเธอว่า
that I'd take her,
ปีนี้รับปาก
and our son out this year.
จะพาเธอกับลูกไปเที่ยว
I reneged twice.
แต่ก็ทำไม่ได้ทั้งสองครั้ง
I was thinking
ทีแรกคิดว่าสิ้นปีนี้
of taking them out by year-end.
จะพาเธอกับลูกออกไปเที่ยว
I fibbed.
ปลอบใจเธอหน่อย
What should I say?
จะบอกเธอยังไงดี
Get me my medical record
นายเอาประวัติ
and examination report.
กับผลตรวจมาให้ฉัน
I'll take them to hospital myself.
ฉันจะเอาไปโรงพยาบาลเอง
Bear this in mind
อย่าลืมด้วยนะ
that if I hadn't sensed something wrong,
ถ้าไม่ใช่เพราะฉันรู้สึกผิดปกติ
I'd be pressing the doctor for answers.
เค้นถามเอาจากหมอ
You weren't
นายก็คง
planning to tell me?
ไม่คิดจะบอกฉันใช่ไหม
I...
คือว่าผม
haven't come up with what to say.
ไม่รู้เริ่มต้นยังไง
Neither have I.
ฉันเองก็ไม่รู้เหมือนกัน
(Jingjing: I'm off to a business trip. Don't know when I'll be back.)
(เฉียวจิงจิง)
(All-time Records)
(ประวัติการเล่น)
Mengmeng,
เมิ่งเมิ่ง
it's breakfast time.
มากินข้าวได้แล้ว
Mom, have you figured out
แม่ครับ โจทย์คะแนนเสริม
how to solve this additional problem?
แม่คิดออกหรือยังครับ
Wei Wei said,
เวยเวยบอกว่า
her dad came up with two solutions.
พ่อของเธอคิดวิธีแก้ได้สองวิธีแล้ว
Your phone.
มือถือ
Now eat.
กินข้าวก่อน
Have you figured it out?
แม่คิดออกหรือยังครับ
What grade are you?
นี่ลูกเพิ่งจะกี่ขวบเอง
Can a math problem be so hard?
ทำไมโจทย์คณิตศาสตร์ยากขนาดนี้
My teacher said, it's an additional problem.
คุณครูบอกว่าเป็นโจทย์คะแนนเสริม
Take it or leave it.
จะทำหรือไม่ทำก็ได้
But it'll be a shame to leave it.
แต่ถ้าไม่ทำก็จะขายหน้านะครับ
So...
เอาเป็นว่า
You haven't figured it out, did you?
แม่คิดไม่ออกใช่ไหม
You're not as good as dad.
บอกแล้วว่าพ่อเก่งที่สุด
He'd know.
พ่อต้องทำได้แน่
Is this your homework
นี่เป็นการบ้านของลูก
or mine?
หรือว่าการบ้านของแม่
My teacher said,
คุณครูบอกว่า
you can ask your parents.
ให้ผู้ปกครองช่วยทำได้
Maybe,
ไม่แน่นะ
they wanted to test the parents' IQ.
อาจจะอยากทดสอบผู้ปกครองก็ได้
Mom,
แม่ครับ
are you a little slow up there?
แม่ไม่ฉลาดใช่ไหมครับ
Then I inherited it from you.
แล้วผมก็ได้ยีนจากแม่
Only very few people are as smart
พ่อของลูกเป็นพวกฉลาดผิดปกติ
as your father.
เป็นประเภทที่มีน้อย
I am only of
แม่ของลูกต่างหาก
average IQ.
ถือว่าอยู่ในระดับไอคิวปกติ
I'm not slow or anything.
ไม่เกี่ยวกับโง่หรือฉลาด
I'm not so sure about that.
มันก็ไม่แน่นะครับ
Remember Uncle Yu
อย่างคุณอาอวี๋
who dropped by for dinner?
ที่มากินข้าวบ้านเราคราวก่อน
I had one question I couldn't answer,
ผมมีโจทย์ที่ทำไม่ได้
but he managed to answer it
คุณอาดูแค่แป๊บเดียว
at just one glance.
ก็หาคำตอบได้เลย
Uncle Yu
คุณอาอวี๋ของลูก
graduated from Tsinghua.
เขาจบมหาวิทยาลัยชิงหวาเลยนะ
He's awesome enough
จบทีเดียวสองปริญญาเลย
to earn two degrees.
พวกบ้าคลั่ง
That puts him
อย่างเขาเนี่ย
in the same league as your dad.
จัดอยู่ประเภทเดียวกับพ่อของลูก
Coming.
มาแล้ว
Who is it so early in the morning?
ใครเนี่ยมาแต่เช้าเชียว
Eat up.
กินไปก่อนนะ
Your savior is here.
ฮีโร่ของลูกมาแล้ว
There are two kinds.
สองแบบแล้ว
Dad, write another,
พ่อครับ ถ้าพ่อเขียนอีกแบบ
and I'll be the first in my class.
ผมก็ได้ที่หนึ่งของห้องเลยนะ
Wait till you see.
รอเดี๋ยวนะ
Plus four...
บวกอีกสี่
Multiply by...
คูณด้วย
Done.
เสร็จแล้ว
I'm the first in my class!
ผมได้ที่หนึ่งของห้องแล้ว
But I'll hold it back
ผมต้องเก็บไว้ก่อน
from my class for now.
ไม่บอกในกลุ่มชั้นเรียน
Then I'll show them tomorrow.
แล้วพรุ่งนี้ค่อยเอาออกมาโชว์
No one can surpass me
ใครที่คิดจะแซงหน้าผม
by then.
ก็คงไม่ทันแล้ว
I wonder who he inherited his wit from.
จอมวางแผนนะเนี่ย ไม่รู้ว่าเหมือนใคร
All right.
เอาล่ะ
You should pack up
ลูกไปเก็บของได้แล้วจ้ะ
and head for hobby class.
ต้องไปเรียนพิเศษแล้ว
I'll pick you up at noon
เดี๋ยวตอนเที่ยงแม่ไปรับ
and we'll have delicious lunch.
กลับมากินข้าวดีไหมจ๊ะ
I don't want to go to hobby class.
ผมไม่อยากเรียนพิเศษ
It's not every Sunday that dad is home.
นาน ๆ พ่อจะอยู่บ้านวันอาทิตย์
I want to be with him.
ผมอยากอยู่กับพ่อ
You have no class in the afternoon.
ช่วงบ่ายลูกไม่มีเรียน
You'll have time to be with him.
ค่อยกลับมาเล่นกับพ่อนะ
Hurry up and get changed.
เร็วเข้า รีบไปเปลี่ยนเสื้อผ้า
I'm not so sure about that.
มันก็ไม่แน่
You know how elusive dad is.
พ่อชอบหายตัวบ่อย ๆ
I'm afraid he'll disappear
ไม่แน่พอกลับมาช่วงบ่าย
by afternoon.
พ่ออาจไม่อยู่ก็ได้
Then ask your dad,
ก็ลองถามพ่อดูสิ
"Will you wander away?"
ว่าจะไปไหนอีกไหม
I'm home now.
พ่ออยู่เซี่ยงไฮ้
No business trips.
ไม่ไปนอกเมืองแล้ว
Hello?
ฮัลโหล
What you asked me this morning,
เรื่องเมื่อเช้าที่เธอถามฉัน
Kings got back to me.
Honor of Kings โทรกลับมาแล้ว
The competition
การแข่งขันจะใช้
will use today's updated version.
ตัวอัพเดทของวันนี้จริง ๆ
There could be new heroes.
อาจมีตัวฮีโร่ใหม่ ๆ ด้วย
So can I try out one of them?
งั้นฉันลองเล่นตัวฮีโร่ใหม่นะคะ
The equipment could use a little adjustment.
ต้องปรับอาวุธใหม่ด้วย
Sorry for the trouble.
ไม่เบานะเนี่ย
About a month ago, you were a newbie at this.
เมื่อเดือนก่อนเธอยังไม่รู้เรื่องอะไรเลย
And now, you're an expert.
ตอนนี้เป็นคนในวงการไปแล้ว
You even took notice of details
แม้แต่การแข่งขันจะใช้เวอร์ชั่นอะไร
like what version to use.
ยังรู้จักสังเกตด้วย
Well?
เป็นยังไงบ้าง
Any idea?
พอจะมั่นใจไหม
In e-sports,
กีฬาอีสปอร์ต
I could be wrong,
เอาแน่เอานอนไม่ได้
but there can't possibly be any shoo-ins.
ไม่มีใครรู้ว่าจะเป็นผู้ชนะแน่ ๆ
Even pros will lose.
เกมเมอร์อาชีพก็ยังแพ้ได้
And I'm no exception.
ฉันก็แพ้ได้เหมือนกันค่ะ
The least I can do
ขอแค่ทำผลงาน
is to show off
ของตัวเองให้ดีที่สุด
the very best of me.
ก็พอแล้ว
I think
ฉันก็รู้สึกว่า
you shouldn't push yourself too hard.
อย่ากดดันตัวเองมากเกินไปเหมือนกัน
Besides,
อีกอย่างนะ
I think you're doing
ฉันว่าตอนนี้เธอ
really great at it.
เล่นได้ดีเลยนะ
Look at you.
ดูเธอสิ
You're in Ace 2.
ได้แรงค์สตาร์ไซน์ระดับสองเชียว
Right?
ใช่ไหม
As for Mr. Yu,
แล้ว อาจารย์อวี๋
he is
ช่วงนี้
not teaching you lately?
ไม่ได้มาสอนเลยหรอ
I can climb the ranks myself,
ฉันเข้าเกมเองได้
whether he's around or not.
เขาจะมาไม่มาไม่เห็นเกี่ยวเลย
I have a script to read.
ฉันอ่านบทก่อนนะ
You're excused.
พี่ทำงานต่อเถอะ
Okay.
ได้
Goodbye then.
งั้นวางแล้วนะ
(Ace)
(แรงค์สตาร์ไชน์ สามดาว)
(Jade Rabbit Pounding Elixir...)
(กระต่ายหยกตำยา ชวนคุณ ร่วมทีมแข่งโหมดแรงค์กิ้ง)
(Yes.)
(ออกจากทีม)
(Jade Rabbit Pounding Elixir invites you to team up at 5v5 Valley of Kings)
(กระต่ายหยกตำยา ชวนคุณ ร่วมทีมแข่งโหมดแรงค์กิ้ง)
(Destroy Enemy Defenses)
(ทำลายป้อมศัตรู)
(Vanquish)
(เหมียนฮวาที่เอื้อมเด็ดถึง จัดการคู่ต่อสู้สำเร็จ)
(Invincible)
(เหมียนฮวาที่เอื้อมเด็ดถึง แผลงฤทธิ์)
(Congrats on your winning streak. I won 10 times in a row.)
(ชนะรวดครั้งที่สิบ)
Jingjing.
จิงจิง
What's Mr. Yu doing downstairs?
ทำไมอาจารย์อวี๋อยู่ข้างล่างล่ะ
Are you going to leave him
เธอทิ้งเขาไว้ข้างล่าง
stranded down there?
ไม่ยอมให้ขึ้นมาใช่ไหม
♪You crossed the sea of ​​stars and came with light♪
♪เธอมาจากฟากฟ้า มาพร้อมกับแสงสว่าง♪
(Jade Rabbit Pounding Elixir invites you to team up at 5v5 Valley of Kings)
(กระต่ายหยกตำยา ชวนคุณ ร่วมทีมแข่งโหมดแรงค์กิ้ง)
♪My heart is like the dust, and I couldn't bear to stain the hemline♪
♪หัวใจฉันเปรียบเหมือนฝุ่น ไม่อยากแปดเปื้อนกระโปรงของเธอ♪
♪To love in a different way,♪
♪ความรักที่ไม่เหมือนใคร ดอกไม้ไฟที่ดวงดาวยังชายตามอง♪
♪I turn around and realize that my heart is empty ♪
♪หันกลับมาจึงเข้าใจ หัวใจนี้ยังว่างเปล่า♪
♪I miss the overflowing galaxy surging into the sea♪
♪ความคิดถึงท่วมท้นจักรวาล เอ่อล้นจนเต็มท้องทะเล♪
♪Even the fireworks desire to give the stars a future♪
♪ดอกไม้ไฟอยากเป็นที่พึ่งพิงให้ดวงดาว♪
♪As long as you are around♪
♪ขอเพียงแค่มีเธออยู่♪
♪Even the fireworks fear to bloom♪
♪ดอกไม้ไฟกลัวจะแตกแล้วดับไป♪
♪Looking at you, the light in your eyes dimmed♪
♪มองดูนัยน์ตาของเธอ แสงไฟค่อย ๆ เลือนหาย♪
♪I laughed at myself and that I deserve it ♪
♪ทำได้แต่สมน้ำหน้าตัวเอง♪
Are you still angry?
ยังโกรธอยู่ไหม
♪My heart skips a beat, but I'm afraid♪
♪ฉันใจสั่น♪
♪I dreamed of starlight pulling the sleeves♪
♪ฉันฝันเห็นแสงดาวระยิบระยับ บนชายแขนเสื้อ♪
♪A white top covering the thin shoulders♪
♪ชุดสีขาว ปกคลุมหัวไหล่อันซูบเซียว♪
♪I have seen the wounds healed with each passing year♪
♪ฉันเห็นกาลเวลาเยียวยาบาดแผลได้♪
♪There will always be people running towards eternity♪
♪ยังไงก็มีคนไล่ตามชั่วฟ้าดินสลาย♪
♪The bustling intersection♪
♪ท่ามกลางทางแยกผู้คนพลุกพล่าน♪
♪Looking back all of a sudden under the dim light♪
♪แสงไฟริบหรี่ เหลียวหลังมองไป♪
♪I loved your eyes looking at the starry sky♪
♪เคยรักเธอ ท้องฟ้าดวงดาวพร่างพรู เสมือนหนึ่งนัยน์ตาที่สงบนิ่ง♪
♪And I loved the universe in your heart♪
♪ก็เคยรักเธอ ในใจฉันเธอคือทุกอย่าง ในจักรวาล♪
♪Time does not stop, remember the time that we failed to treasure♪
♪กาลเวลาไม่เคยหยุดรอ เก็บซ่อนความเสียใจในสิ่งที่ทำไปตลอดเวลา♪
♪The wind passes by the tall buildings with no one awaiting it♪
♪ลมพัดผ่าน บนตึกสูง ไม่มีใครเฝ้ารออีกต่อไป♪
♪I've dreamed of traveling around the planet♪
♪ฉันก็เคยคิดฝันท่องไปตามดวงดาว♪
♪Seeing the galaxy pass through the clouds♪
♪ผ่านมวลเมฆ ดูทางช้างเผือกที่หลั่งไหล♪
♪I looked at the hills with sorrow♪
♪ฉันเคยมองขุนเขาอย่างเศร้าหมอง♪
♪Will the exit of the dream lead to the end of the starry sky?♪
♪ทางออกแห่งฝัน อยู่ที่สุดขอบทะเลดาวหรือไม่♪
♪Looking back all of a sudden♪
♪เหลียวหลังมองไป♪
♪Which galaxy am I drifting on?♪
♪ฉันล่องลอยอยู่บนทะเลดาวสายไหนกัน♪
♪Looking into the distance, which of the stars are your eyes?♪
♪เฝ้ามองว่าดาวดวงไหนคือนัยน์ตาเธอ♪
♪It's out of reach, so dazzling and hard to get♪
♪ดาวระยิบระยับ เอื้อมไม่ถึงครอบครองไม่ได้♪
♪Time does not hold back, the spring and autumn in the passing time♪
♪กาลเวลาไม่รอใคร เมื่อเวลาผ่าน สรรพสิ่งก็เปลี่ยนไป อดีตจบสิ้นลง♪
♪The wind sings the song of freedom as I listen to the tenderness of time♪
♪สายลมขับร้องอิสรภาพ ฉันตั้งใจฟังห้วงเวลาอันอ่อนโยนละมุนใจ♪